RAJ KUMAR SHAHU

921-240 Wellesley St. E, Toronto, ON, M4X 1G5
Phone: 647-302-7237 | Email: rajkumarshahu@gmail.com
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/rajshahu/ | GitHub: https://github.com/rajkumarshahu
Portfolio: https://rajkumarshahu.com/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web and Mobile Developer with a focus on Front End development. Acquired hands-on experience in MERN stack technologies for the projects during completions of Coding Boot Camp at the University of Toronto. Additionally, acquired knowledge in various programming languages like JavaScript, C#, Java, Python during studies at George Brown College. Developed knowledge of professional communications, administrative duties, and computer hardware and networking through the combination of training and hard work. Recently, learned various aspects of Mobile Application Development from Centennial College. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to develop user-friendly applications. Known among team members for strong wit and attention to detail

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, C#, Java, Python, Swift **Libraries and Framework**: ReactJS, Express.js, React Native

Database Management: MySQL, MongoDB

Server Environment: Node.js

Collaborative Tools: GitHub, Jira, Agile Methods

RECENT PROJECTS

La Villa Pasta REST API

- GitHub: https://github.com/rajkumarshahu/la-villa-pasta-backend
- **API:** https://la-villa-pasta-backend.herokuapp.com/
- About: REST API for La Villa Pasta Mobile Application to manage items, orders and users
- Role: Complete implementation of Web Server with tests and documentation.
- Tools/languages used: Express, Nodejs, MongoDB, Swagger UI, Mocha and Chai

WeCare Mobile Application

- GitHub (Ionic Version): https://github.com/rajkumarshahu/WeCareApp_Ionic_v1
- GitHub (React Native Version): https://github.com/rajkumarshahu/WeCareApp_testing
- **About:** A mobile application for managing patients and their medical records.
- Role: Frontend as well as Backend developer.
- Tools / languages used: React Native, Ionic, Angular, MongoDB, Firebase Authentication, Nodejs, Express

EXPERIENCE

React Developer Intern CheaprEats

2020 March – 2020 August Toronto, Canada

Involved in specifying types for the backend code using JSDoc, created new ServiceProviders that contain all business logic, and make Controllers use that service instead of directly having business logic inside. Additionally, involved in writing integration tests and designing Database Migration System

Key Accomplishments:

• Designed Database Migration System

• Implemented JsDoc for the majority of GraphQL API

Security Guard 2013 – 2017

Defender Security Toronto, Canada

Performed patrol duties within assigned areas to guard against theft, vandalism and fire and prepared detailed reports and records.

Key Accomplishments:

- Prevented vandalism several times by being vigilant and chasing away vandals.
- Communicated with construction workers and explained the safety rules.

Supervisor 2009 – 2013

Marsh Wholesale Europe Ltd

London, UK

Supervised a team of more than 20 staff who worked in production *Key Accomplishments*:

- Communicated effectively among the staff to meet the deadline.
- Promoted products to maximize sales

Coordinator and Content Director

2003 - 2009

Midas Technologies

Kathmandu, Nepal

Coordinated a team of technical and nontechnical staffs while writing and finalizing contents *Key Accomplishments:*

- Wrote and finalized content for more than 35 multimedia based interactive educational software and websites that are developed using HTML, CSS, JavaScript & Flash.
- Participated in promoting the products during exhibitions

EDUCATION

Mobile Applications Development:

September 2020 – Till Now

Centennial College, Toronto, ON, Canada

A 1-year full time program focused on developing Native and Cross Platform mobile applications with emphasis on iOS app development using UIKit and SwiftUI, Android using Kotlin and Java, and Cross Platform application development using React Native and Ionic.

University of Toronto SCS Coding Boot Camp:

June 2019 – September 2019

University of Toronto School of Continuing Studies, Toronto, ON, Canada

A 12-week full-time intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Computer Programmer Analyst:

2017 - 2019

George Brown College, Toronto, ON, Canada

A 3-year full-time program with the coursework focused on Programming and Software design with emphasis on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, C#, Java, Python, ReactJS, Agile methodologies

Master of Business Administration:

2010 - 2011

Cardiff Metropolitan University, LSC campus, London, UK

A 1-year full-time program with the coursework emphases on Marketing, Corporate Finance, Management Information System, Project Management and Strategic Management